<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Weidan Xiong</title>
    <link>/</link>
      <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Weidan Xiong</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>XIONG WEIDAN©2024</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Weidan Xiong</title>
      <link>/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>LightUrban: Similarity Based Fine-grained Instancing for Lightweighting Complex Urban Point Clouds</title>
      <link>/project/lighturban/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/lighturban/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Large-scale urban point clouds play a vital role in various applications, while rendering and transmitting such data remains challenging due to its large volume, complicated structures, and significant redundancy. In this paper, we present LightUrban, the first point cloud instancing framework for efficient rendering and transmission of fine-grained complex urban scenes. We first introduce a segmentation method to organize the point clouds into individual buildings and vegetation instances from coarse to fine.Next, we propose an unsupervised similarity detection approach to accurately group instances with similar shapes. Furthermore, a fast pose and size estimation component is applied to calculate the transformations between the representative instance and the corresponding similar instances in each group. By replacing individual instances with their group&amp;rsquo;s representative instances, the data volume and redundancy can be dramatically reduced. Experimental results on large-scale urban scenes demonstrate the effectiveness of our algorithm. To sum up, our method not only structures the urban point clouds but also significantly reduces data volume and redundancy, filling the gap in point cloud instancing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>纹理贴图的视角选择和纹理对齐软件</title>
      <link>/tmp/patent/textureselectionsoftware/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/tmp/patent/textureselectionsoftware/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>基于扩散模型的建筑纹理贴图补全软件</title>
      <link>/tmp/patent/texturesoftware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/tmp/patent/texturesoftware/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>图像补全方法、装置、计算机设备和存储介质</title>
      <link>/tmp/patent/textureinpainting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/tmp/patent/textureinpainting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TwinTex: Geometry-aware Texture Generation for Abstracted 3D Architectural Models</title>
      <link>/project/twintex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/twintex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coarse architectural models are often generated at scales ranging from individual buildings to scenes for downstream applications such as Digital Twin City, Metaverse, LODs, etc. Such piece-wise planar models can be abstracted as twins from 3D dense reconstructions. However, these models typically lack realistic texture relative to the real building or scene, making them unsuitable for vivid display or direct reference. In this paper, we present TwinTex, the first automatic texture mapping framework to generate a photo-realistic texture for a piece-wise planar proxy. Our method addresses most challenges occurring in such twin texture generation. Specifically, for each primitive plane, we first select a small set of photos with greedy heuristics considering photometric quality, perspective quality and facade texture completeness. Then, different levels of line features (LoLs) are extracted from the set of selected photos to generate guidance for later steps. With LoLs, we employ optimization algorithms to align texture with geometry from local to global. Finally, we fine-tune a diffusion model with a multi-mask initialization component and a new dataset to inpaint the missing region. Experimental results on many buildings, indoor scenes and man-made objects of varying complexity demonstrate the generalization ability of our algorithm. Our approach surpasses state-of-the-art texture mapping methods in terms of high-fidelity quality and reaches a human-expert production level with much less effort.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>一种用于纹理贴图的视角选择和纹理对齐方法及相关设备</title>
      <link>/tmp/patent/textureselection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/tmp/patent/textureselection/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Product Design and Engineering Analysis Techniques, Chapter 2</title>
      <link>/project/book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digital Manufacturing: The Industrialization of &amp;ldquo;Art to Part&amp;rdquo; 3D Additive Printing explains everything needed to understand how recent advances in materials science, manufacturing engineering and digital design have integrated to create exciting new capabilities. Sections discuss relevant fundamentals in mechanical engineering and materials science and complex and practical topics in additive manufacturing, such as part manufacturing, all in the context of the modern digital design environment. Being successful in today’s &amp;ldquo;art to part&amp;rdquo; cyber-physical manufacturing age requires a strong grounding in science and engineering fundamentals as well as knowledge of the latest techniques, all of which readers will find here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every chapter is developed by leading specialists and based on first-hand experiences, capturing the essential knowledge readers need to solve problems related to digital manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Product Design and Engineering Analysis Techniques, Chapter 2, Digital Manufacturing</title>
      <link>/publication/3dpbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/3dpbook/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShapeArchit: Shape-inspired Architecture Design with Space Planning</title>
      <link>/project/shapearchit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/shapearchit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Various techniques have been proposed to improve the level of automation in architectural design life-cycle. We present an interactive interface, along with geometric algorithms focused on designing early stage symbolic architecture. First, the architect specifies some simple shape requirements by inputting a few binary images that resemble the shape of the building from different viewpoints. These are used to generate a conceptual design that is guided by various aesthetic and structural requirements. Second, we explore an interactive technique in planning the inner space of the given architecture model. The architect specifies the ideal requirements on the key functional rooms by using instances of simple 3D primitive shapes. The pose and location of each instance are parameters in multi-objectives. By coupling this process together with the shape inspired exterior design process, we can construct good initial conceptual designs. To solve these problems, we develop modified cuckoo search algorithms. Furthermore, a novel iterative mesh smoothing algorithm that yields a smooth surface while preserving sharp creases and generating roof structures is also developed. Several examples are presented to illustrate the methodology and results. User studies based on a proposed dataset and interviews with domain experts have been carried out to demonstrate the usability and effectiveness of our system and algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShapeArchit: Shape-inspired Architecture Design with Space Planning</title>
      <link>/publication/shapearchit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/shapearchit/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architectural Design from Sketches</title>
      <link>/tmp/talk/2021workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/tmp/talk/2021workshop/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rationalizing Architectural Surfaces Based on Clustering of Joints</title>
      <link>/project/remeshing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/remeshing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We introduce the problem of clustering the set of vertices in a given 3D mesh. The problem is motivated by the need for value engineering in architectural projects. We first derive a max-norm based metric to estimate the geometric disparity between a given pair of vertices, and characterize the problem in terms of this measure. We show that this distance can be computed by using Sequential Quadratic Programming (SQP). Next we introduce two different algorithms for clustering the set of vertices on a given mesh, respectively based on two disparity measurements: max-norm and L2-norm based metric. An equivalence is established between mesh vertices and physical joints in an architectural mesh. By replacing individual joints by their equivalent cluster representative, the number of unique joints in the facade mesh, and therefore the fabrication cost, is dramatically reduced. Finally, we present an algorithm for remeshing a given surface in order to further reduce the number of joint clusters. The framework is tested for a set of real-world architectural surfaces to illustrate the effectiveness and utility of our approach. Overall, this approach tackles the important problem reducing fabrication cost of joints without modifying the underlying connectivity that was specified by the architect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rationalizing Architectural Surfaces Based on Clustering of Joints</title>
      <link>/publication/remeshing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/remeshing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Element Placement on 3D Surfaces</title>
      <link>/tmp/patent/porepatent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/tmp/patent/porepatent/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Part Design with Additive Manufacturing</title>
      <link>/tmp/talk/2020webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/tmp/talk/2020webinar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>/tmp/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/tmp/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-slides&#34;&gt;Welcome to Slides&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = \;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   Three
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/img/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/img/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shape-Inspired Architecture Design</title>
      <link>/tmp/talk/2018webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/tmp/talk/2018webinar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shape-inspired Architecture Design</title>
      <link>/project/shape/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/shape/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We introduce a method to design architectural buildings that are inspired by shapes of non-architectural forms. The user inputs a few binary images, each providing an indicative shape for the building from a different viewpoint. A discrete visual hull corresponding to each binary image is generated. A voxel model is then constructed by intersecting the hulls corresponding to the images. The shape of the voxel model depends on the parameters of the projections. Real buildings must also obey some topological and structural constraints. We develop a shape metric to evaluate a given design in terms of topological, functional and structural requirements of the building. This allows us to optimize the building shape as a function of the parameters of the projection. The optimization problem is solved by means of an improved cuckoo search metaheuristic. The resulting voxel model is converted into a mesh model. Finally, we apply a novel smoothing algorithm that produces a smooth surface while preserving sharp creases and roof structures. Several examples are presented in the paper to illustrate the methodology and results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shape-Inspired Architectural Design</title>
      <link>/publication/shape/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/shape/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
